# Curriculum Vitae Nathan M. Smith Jr.

Director of Technology Integration Emma Eccles Jones College of Education and Human Services Utah State University

> 2845 Old Main Hill Utah State Univeristy, Logan, UT 84322-2845

> > Nathan.Smith@USU.edu 435 • 797 • 1484

## **Biography**

Nathan Smith currently serves as the Director of Technology Integration for the Emma Eccles Jones College of Education and Human Services at Utah State University. In that role, he directs the Adele and Dale Young Education Technology Center (YETC). The YETC serves the college as a K-12 curriculum library, student-open access computer facility, Utah's NASA Regional Educator Resource Center, and a technology training and service center. He teaches the required technology integration course for pre-service educators at Utah State University. He also teaches beginning and advanced Photoshop and graphic design courses. He enjoys learning and sharing educational resources worldwide through his TeacherLINK website. He has participated in training IREX/TEA high school teachers from all over the world, including training for Lebanese and Jordanian teachers in Amman, Jordan. He serves on the board of directors for the Utah Coalition for Educational Technology. He has been invited to serve on the board of directors for the Center for Creativity, Innovation, and Discovery, a new charter school focused on project-based learning in Providence, Utah.

## **Education**

1989-90	Utah State University - Instructional Technology and Learning Sciences Master of Science
1977-80	Brigham Young University - Elementary Education - Minor: Art Bachelor of Science

### **Work Experience**

2016-Present	Director of Technology Integration College of Education and Human Services, Utah State University
2000-16	Director of Technology College of Education and Human Services, Utah State University
1992-2000	Associate Director Adele and Dale Young Education Technology Center/NASA Regional Educator Resource Center College of Education and Human Services, Utah State University 2845 Old Main Hill, Utah State University, Logan, UT 84322-2845
1980-1992	Elementary School Teacher

Santa Clara Elementary School, 2950 Crestview Dr, Santa Clara, UT 84765

## **Outreach Experience**

2017-Present	Board of Directors, The Center for Creativity, Innovation and Discovery (CCID) 67 South Sherwood Drive, Providence, UT 84332
2011-Present	Assist with the Utah State University GearUp grant program. http://utahstars.usu.edu
2005-Present	Board of Directors, The Utah Coalition for Educational Technology (UCET) http://ucet.org
2016-12-16	Presented to District Science Specialists and Technology Specialists from the Granite, Alpine, Salt Lake, and Weber School Districts
2016-10-13	Trained Space Dynamics Laboratory employees on basic Photoshop skills
2016-09-23	Trained Sky View High School faculty about technology integration resources
2016-08-17	Presented at the Empowering Teaching Excellence Conference - USU "Integrating Technology and Innovation in Education" https://empowerteaching.usu.edu/conference
2016-06-13	Presented to the Merrill-Cazier Library Faculty and Staff "New Technologies that Will Impact Libraries and Education"
2015-11-06/07	Presented at SUECON (Southern Utah Education Conference) "Photoshop Training" and "Teaching STEM? Great NASA Resources" https://www.suecon.org
2015-04-02/03	Presented at the Utah Coalition for Educational Technology Conference "Beginning Photoshop" and "Advanced Photoshop" http://www.ucet.org
2015-01-16	Presented to Mount Logan Middle School faculty and staff "New technologies for teachers"
2015-12-05	Presented to Elementary Education students at Brigham Young University "NASA Resources for Teachers"
2015-11-07	Presented at the Southern Utah Educators Conference
2015-04-06	Presented to Elementary Education Students at Brigham Young University
2015-04-02/03	Presented to Utah educators at the annual conference for the Utah Coalition for Educational Technology
2015-01-16	Presented to faculty of the Mount Logan Middle School, Logan, Utah
2014-12-05	Presented to Elementary Education Students at Brigham Young University
2014-12-04	Train Mt. Logan Middle School students about technology
2014-04-03/04	Presented to Utah educators at the annual conference for the Utah Coalition for Educational Technology - Advanced Photoshop
2013-12-06 Friday	Presented to Elementary Education students at Brigham Young University - Science
2013-11-01/02	Presented at the Southern Utah Educators Conference - NASA Resources - Photoshop
2013-10-02	Train faculty at Judge Memorial High School, Salt Lake City, Utah

2013-09-18/19	Presented at the GearUP conference in Salt Lake City, Utah
2013-06-12	Salt Lake City - Photoshop Resources presentation to CTE Conference - Murray High School
2013-04-10/17	U.S. State Department trip to Amman, Jordan to train teachers and administrators from Lebanon and Jordan in the use of educational technologies
2013-03-01/03	Presented at Four Corners School of Outdoor Education Conference, Blanding, UT
2012-12-11	Presented to Cache School District Principals about technology resources
2012-09/11	Trained 22 high school teachers from around the world about educational technologies U.S. State Department's IREX/TEA program.
2011-10-13/14	Presented at the Southern Utah Educators Conference, St. George, UT
2011-09-14	Presented to Edith Bowen Laboratory School Faculty - Technology resources
2011-09/11	Trained 20 high school teachers from around the world about educational technologies U.S. State Department's IREX/TEA program

## **Teaching Experience (See attached IDEA Class Evaluations)**

ITLS 5500: Innovative Integration of Technology in Education

ITLS 5230/6230: Instructional Graphics Production I - Beginning Photoshop and Graphic Design

ITLS 5240/6240: Instructional Graphics Production 2 - Advanced Photoshop and Graphic Design

I also teach technology sessions for many of the various college courses offered in the College of Education and Human Services at Utah State University.

## Acquired Skills (Scale of 1-5, 5 is expert level.)

				•			
	Smith, Nathan					Comparison G	roup = IDEA
Overall Average			A - Pro	gress on Relevant Obj	ectives		
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	dl .	2016 Spring
62	Much Higher Higher 57 Similar TLS 5275,6275 Lower	68 ITLS 5240,6240	60 ITLS 5240,6240	65 ITLS 5230; 6230	61 ITLS 5230, 6230	55 ITLS 5500	6 <u>4</u> ITLS 5240, 6240
Higher	Much Lower						
Overall Average				B - Excellent Teacher			
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	II	2016 Spring
57	Much Higher Higher Similar 50 Lower ITLS 5275,6275	63 !TLS 5240,6240	54 ITLS 5240,6240	69 ITLS 5230, 6230	58 ITLS 5230, 6230	52 !TLS 5500	63 ITLS 5 <b>2£</b> 0, 6240 ITLS 5240, 6240
Higher	Much Lower						
Overall Average				C - Excellent Course			
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	II	2016 Spring
60	Much Higher Higher Similar 1TLS 5275,6275 Lower	67 ITLS 5240,6240	59 ITLS 5240,6240	ITLS 5230; 6230	61 ITLS 5230, 6230	49 ITLS 5500	68 ITLS 580, 6240 ITLS 5240, 6240
Higher	Much Lower					1120 0000	
Overall Average			ı	O - Summary Evaluation	n		
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	II	2016 Spring
61	Much Higher Higher 55 Similar TLS 5275.6275	67 ITLS 5240,6240	59 ITLS 5240,6240		61 ITLS 5230, 6230	53 ITLS 5500	[FLS 5240; 6240
Higher	Lower Much Lower						

				•			
	Smith, Nathan					Comparison G	roup = IDEA
Overall Average			A - Pro	gress on Relevant Obj	ectives		
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	dl .	2016 Spring
62	Much Higher Higher 57 Similar TLS 5275,6275 Lower	68 ITLS 5240,6240	60 ITLS 5240,6240	65 ITLS 5230; 6230	61 ITLS 5230, 6230	55 ITLS 5500	6 <u>4</u> ITLS 5240, 6240
Higher	Much Lower						
Overall Average				B - Excellent Teacher			
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	II	2016 Spring
57	Much Higher Higher Similar 50 Lower ITLS 5275,6275	63 !TLS 5240,6240	54 ITLS 5240,6240	69 ITLS 5230, 6230	58 ITLS 5230, 6230	52 !TLS 5500	63 ITLS 5 <b>2£</b> 0, 6240 ITLS 5240, 6240
Higher	Much Lower						
Overall Average				C - Excellent Course			
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	II	2016 Spring
60	Much Higher Higher Similar 1TLS 5275,6275 Lower	67 ITLS 5240,6240	59 ITLS 5240,6240	ITLS 5230; 6230	61 ITLS 5230, 6230	49 ITLS 5500	68 ITLS 580, 6240 ITLS 5240, 6240
Higher	Much Lower					1120 0000	
Overall Average			ı	O - Summary Evaluation	n		
	2013 Spring	2014 Spring	2015 Spring	2015 Fall	2016 Fa	II	2016 Spring
61	Much Higher Higher 55 Similar TLS 5275.6275	67 ITLS 5240,6240	59 ITLS 5240,6240		61 ITLS 5230, 6230	53 ITLS 5500	[FLS 5240; 6240
Higher	Lower Much Lower						

	Smith, Nathan		ITLS 5230, 6230	Comparison Group = IDEA
Overall Average			A - Progress on Relevant Objectives	
		2015 Fall		2016 Fall
63	Much Higher Higher Similar Lower	65 ITLS 5239; 6239		61 iTLS 5230, 6230
Much Hig	Much Lower			
Overall Average			B - Excellent Teacher	
		2015 Fall		2016 Fall
59	Much Higher Higher Similar	99 ITLS 8230, 8230		58 ITLS 5230, 6230
Higher	Lower Much Lower			
ing.io.				
Overall Average			C - Excellent Course	
		2015 Fall		2016 Fall
63	Much Higher Higher Similar	ITLS 5230; 6230		61 ITLS 5230, 6230
Much Hig	Lower Much Lower			
Overall Average			D - Summary Evaluation	
		2015 Fall		2016 Fall
62	Much Higher Higher Similar			81 ITLS 5230, 6230
Higher	Lower Much Lower			

Smith, Nathan ITLS 5240, 6240 Comparison Group = IDEA Overall Average A - Progress on Relevant Objectives 2016 Spring 63 Much Higher 64 ITLS 5240, 6240 Higher Similar Much Hig.. B - Excellent Teacher **Overall Average** 2016 Spring 59 Much Higher 63 ITLS 5250, 6240 Higher Similar ITLS 5240, 6240 Higher Much Lower Overall Average C - Excellent Course 2016 Spring 68 ITLS 5240, 6240 64 Much Higher Higher Similar Lower Much Lower Much Hig.. **Overall Average D** - Summary Evaluation 2016 Spring 63 Much Higher 64 ITI S 5240, 6240 Higher Similar Higher Much Lower

	Smith, Nathan	ITLS 5275,6275	Comparison Group = IDEA
Overall Average		A - Progress on Relevant Objectives	
		2013 Spring	
57	Much Higher Higher Similar Lower	57 ITLS 5275,6275	
Higher	Much Lower		
Overall Average		B - Excellent Teacher	
		2013 Spring	
50	Much Higher Higher Similar	50	
Cimilar	Lower Much Lower	ITLS 5275,6275	
Similar	Widell Edwer		
Overall Average		C - Excellent Course	
		2013 Spring	
53	Much Higher Higher Similar	53 ITLS 5275,6275	
Similar	Lower Much Lower		
Overall Average		D - Summary Evaluation	
		2013 Spring	
55	Much Higher Higher Similar	55 ITLS 5275.6275	
Similar	Lower Much Lower	11.50 32.50.21 5	
Sillillar			

Smith, Nathan ITLS 5240,6240 Comparison Group = IDEA Overall Average A - Progress on Relevant Objectives 2014 Spring 2015 Spring 68 ITLS 5240,6240 64 60 ITLS 5240,6240 Higher Similar Much Hig.. B - Excellent Teacher **Overall Average** 2015 Spring 2014 Spring 59 Much Higher 63 ITLS 5240,6240 Higher Similar 54 ITLS 5240,6240 Higher Much Lower Overall Average C - Excellent Course 2015 Spring 2014 Spring 67 TILS 5240,6240 63 Much Higher Higher Similar ITLS 5240,6240 Lower Much Hig.. **Overall Average D** - Summary Evaluation 2014 Spring 2015 Spring 63 67 ITLS 5240,6240 Much Higher Higher Similar ITLS 5240,6240 Much Hig.. Much Lower

	Smith, Nathan	ITLS 5500	Comparison Group = IDEA
Overall Average		A - Progress on Relevant Objectives	
		2016 Fall	
55	Much Higher Higher Similar Lower	55 ITLS 5500	
Similar	Much Lower		
Overall Average		B - Excellent Teacher	
		2016 Fall	
52	Much Higher Higher Similar	52 ITLS 5500	
Similar	Lower Much Lower	#150 0000	
Overall Average		C - Excellent Course	
		2016 Fall	
49	Much Higher Higher Similar	49 ITLS 5500	
Similar	Lower Much Lower	ITLS 5500	
Overall Average		D - Summary Evaluation	
		2016 Fall	
53	Much Higher Higher Similar	53	
	Lower	!TLS 5500	
Similar	Much Lower		